A Guide to the Papers of Sarah Patton Boyle, 1949-1970
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Sarah Patton Boyle, 1949-1970
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8003-a,-b
This collection consists of ca. 12,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the library by Ms. Boyle on June 30, 1971.
Alternative Form
Portions available on microfilm as Manuscript Division reel #M-2130.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains correspondence and material concerning Sarah Patton Boyle's The Desegregated Heart and her For Human Beings Only; speeches; editorials; book reviews; and material regarding the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, the Virginia Council on Human Relations, The Congress of Racial Equality, and the Southern Christian leadership Conference.
There are also polls, including the "Parker Poll" on desegregation at the University of Virgiia, miscellaneous clippings and articles, a scrapbook, and a cross which was burned on Mrs. Boyle's lawn.
Contents List
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence: "A" 1968 (Box 1)
  - Ralph D. Abernathy, President, SCLC 1968 June (Box 1)
  - William B. Abbot. Newspaper, The Southern Patriot, February 1959 1955-1961 (Box 1)
  - Rev. Mr. F. E. Alexander 1951-1953 (Box 1)
  - AFL-CIO 1952-1960 (Box 1)
  - Associated Press, with blank legal contract 1961-1964 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: "B" 1951-1968, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Lester Banks, Executive Secretary, Virginia State Conference, NAACP 1951-1965 (Box 1)
  - Stringfellow Barr 1962 Jun 13 (Box 1)
  - Gov. John S. Battle re clemency for Albert Jackson ca. 1952 (Box 1)
    Contains related petitions and newspaper clippings.
  - Hubert Beckwith, President, VCHR 1958-1959 (Box 1)
  - Black Drama, Inc. 1968 (Box 1)
  - Daniel A. Bowers, Executive Director, VCHR 1959-1960 (Box 1)
  - W. Carroll Brooke, President, VCHR 1955 Feb 10 (Box 1)
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd. (publishers) 1954-1955 (Box 1)
  - Harry F. Byrd, Jr. 1968 Jun 17 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: "C" 1951-1968 (Box 1)
  - Omer Carmichael 1955-1958 (Box 1)
  - The Catholic Digest 1963 Jun 6 (Box 1)
  - Dwight M. Chalmers 1957 (Box 1)
  - Charlottesville-Albemarle Tribune 1957 Oct 20 (Box 1)
  - Charlottesville Daily Progress 1953-1955 (Box 1)
  - Marjory Cherry 1955-1958 (Box 1)
    Includes two photographs
  - Chicago Sun-Times 1963 (Box 1)
  - Malcolm Christian 1964 Jan 13 (Box 1)
  - The Christian Century 1952-1968 (Box 1)
  - Winifed (Mrs. Roger) Clapp and Mrs. Samuel L. Abbott, Jr. 1957-1960 (Box 1)
  - The Kenneth Clarks 1963 (Box 1)
  - John and Peggy Collison 1962 (Box 1)
    Includes a typed manuscript of John Collison's play, Mary Douglas.
  - Community 1956 (Box 1)
  - Concern 1952 (Box 1)
  - William M. Cooper, Associate Executive Director, VCHR 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - CORE 1959-1964 (Box 1)
  - Council for Social Action 1954 (Box 1)
    Concerns the election of Boyle as president of the organization, with newspaper clippings and papers concerning the C. S. A. and "Get Out the Vote Contest."
  - John Bolt Culberton, and papers about Boyle's visit to Greenville, South Carolina 1956-1963 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence: "D" 1951-1968 (Box 2)
  - Danville Register 1955 May 25 (Box 2)
  - Colgate W. Darden, Jr. 1955-1957 (Box 2)
  - Deland Sun News 1964 May (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: "E" 1955-1968, n.d. (Box 2)
  - P. E. East, Editor of The Petal Paper, with articles by East 1956-1965, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Ebony 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - The Echo, Furman University 1955 May (Box 2)
  - Murrell Edmunds 1955-1956 (Box 2)
    Contains a typed manuscript of "First Lesson."
  - John M. Ellison 1953-1955 (Box 2)
  - The Episcopalia n 1963-1970 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: "F" 1951-1958 (Box 2)
  - George R. Ferguson, President, Charlottesville Branch, NAACP 1952-1958 (Box 2)
  - Florida Times-Union 1952 Apr 18 (Box 2)
  - "Gerry" [Gerald R.] Ford 1968 Jun 18 (Box 2)
  - Forward Movement Publications 1965-1968 (Box 2)
  - Charles D. Fowler, Jr., President, Charlottesville Branch, NAACP 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - "The Fund for the Republic" re a book grant 1956 (Box 2)
  - Mrs. Paul J. Furnas 1963-1964 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: "G" 1952-1965, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Dr. Sam[uel Gandy] 1952-1953 (Box 2)
  - Harry Golden, Editor of the Carolina Israelite 1958-1963 (Box 2)
  - June P. Guild 1958-1960 (Box 2)
  - Griffin Gunther 1954-1964 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: "H" 1951-1959 (Box 3)
  - Ruth Haefner 1957-1962 (Box 3)
  - Elly Haney 1963-1965 (Box 3)
    Includes copies of two chapters of Haney's dissertation on Boyle's life and work.
  - T. W. Hardy 1955 Feb-Mar (Box 3)
  - Dr. W. Lee Harris 1951-1953 (Box 3)
  - Dennis N. Haughton 1951 (Box 3)
  - Dr. E. B. Henderson 1951 - 1953 (Box 3)
  - Dr. E. B. Henderson 1955-1971 (Box 3)
    Includes typed manuscript "New Responsibilities in Community Relations--From Segregation to Integration."
  - Rev. Raymond Henderson 1957-1964 (Box 3)
  - Thomas Howard Henderson 1957 (Box 3)
    Contains the typed manuscript carbon "What the Negro Wants."
  - Highlander Folk School 1954-1960 (Box 3)
  - Oliver W. Hill, Legal Staff, Virginia State Conference, NAACP 1951-1960 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence: "J" 1951-1959 (Box 4)
  - Lyndon B. Johnson re Peace Corps (copy) 1961 Oct 16 (Box 4)
  - Johnson Publishing Company 1963 (Box 4)
  - E. Theodore Jones 1955-1956 (Box 4)
  - Journal and Guide editors 1952-1958, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: "K" 1953-1967 (Box 4)
  - Martin Luther King 1955-1970 (Box 4)
  - Koinonia Farm 1958-1963 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: "L" 1951-1958 (Box 4)
  - Ladies Home Journal 1955-1956 (Box 4)
  - Jim Lawson 1953-1958 (Box 4)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Heslip M. Lee, Executive Director and Secretary, VCHR 1962-1964 (Box 4)
  - Life 1956 (Box 4)
  - David Longley, Treasurer, Virginia State Conference, NAACP 1952-1953, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
  - Claude E. Love 1953 (Box 4)
  - Lynchburg News and Daily Advance 1955 Apr (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: "M" 1951-1958, n.d. (Box 4)
  - John H. Marion, Executive Director, VCHR 1955-1957 (Box 4)
    See also Southern Regional Council, Inc.
  - McCall's 1957 May 29 (Box 5)
  - Jane (Mrs. Nelson) McClary 1964-1965 (Box 5)
  - James Meredith 1962 Oct (Box 5)
  - Miami Herald and the University of Miami 1952-1955 (Box 5)
  - G. A. Miller, with TLS, Vincent S. Waters to Miller 1953-1962, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Minneapolis Morning Tribune 1952 Sep 17 (Box 5)
  - Clarence Mitchell, Director, Washington Bureau, NAACP 1954, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Henry Lee Moon, Director, Public Relations, NAACP 1955-1960 (Box 5)
  - Charles E. Moran, Jr., Acting President, Charlottesville-Ablemarle Chapter of the VCHR 1956 (Box 5)
  - Flora [Florsch] Morrison 1956-1959 (Box 5)
  - William Morrow & Company, Inc., Publishers 1960-1969, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Motive Magazine 1954 Dec (Box 5)
  - Pauli Murray 1963 (Box 5)
    See microfilm for more correspondence.
  - Correspondence: "N" 1951-1960 (Box 6)
  - The Nation 1956-1958 (Box 6)
  - Norfolk Virginian-Pilot 1956-1958, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Orange and White, University of Tennessee 1955 Dec 27 (Box 6)
  - Narcissa [D.] Overstreet 1958 Nov 17 (Box 6)
  - Dr. Hugo Owens re integration movement in Portsmouth 1958 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: "P" 1952-1960 (Box 6)
  - Susie Peace, Mary Washington College 1952-1958 (Box 6)
  - Pittsburgh Courier 1953-1964 (Box 6)
  - The Presbyterian Outlook 1951-1954 (Box 6)
  - The Progressive 1952-1953 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: "R" 1951-1958 (Box 6)
  - Ramparts Magazine 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Reader's Digest 1952-1964, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Milton A. Reid, President, Virginia Christian Leadership Conference 1960 (Box 6)
  - Richmond Times Dispatch and News Leader, especially with Virginius Dabney and Ben and Janet Johnston, former editors of the Times Dispatch 1951-1963, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Walter N. Ridley, Professor of Psychology, Virginia State College 1953-1957 (Box 6)
  - Paul Rilling, Executive Director, VCHR 1957-1959 (Box 6)
  - Harry W. Roberts, Department of Sociology, Virginia State College 1953-1957 (Box 6)
  - Spottswood W. Robinson, III, Legal Staff, Virginia State Conference, NAACP 1951-1957 (Box 6)
  - John C. Rogers 1951 (Box 6)
  - B. F. D. Runk, Dean of Student Affairs, University of Virginia 1957 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence: "S" 1951-1961, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Saturday Evening Post 1954-1962, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Seabury Press 1963-1969 (Box 6)
  - Leander T. Shaw 1952-1957, n.d. (Box 7)
  - T. J. Sellers, the Amsterdam News 1950-1970, n.d. (Box 7)
  - David McD. Simms 1951-1956, n.d. (Box 7)
  - The Southern Conference Educational Fund, Inc. 1950-1959 (Box 7)
    Includes related Southside Conference on Compliance with the Supreme Court Decision on Segregation in Public Schools.
  - Southern Regional Council, Inc. 1951-1968 (Box 7)
  - William B. Spong, Jr. 1968 Jun 19 (Box 7)
  - Stephen Gill Spottswood, President, District of Columbia Branch, NAACP 1952 (Box 7)
  - Gregory H. Swanson, University of Virginia's first African-American student 1952-1961 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence: "T" 1952-1968 (Box 8)
  - Dr. O. B. Taylor 1950-1952 (Box 8)
    Includes typed manuscript "What Would I Do, If I Were a White Man?"
  - This Week 1956 (Box 8)
  - Irma B. Thompson 1954-1955 (Box 8)
  - J. M. Tinsley, President, Virginia State Conference, NAACP, memo to co-workers 1952 Oct 10 (Box 8)
  - E. A. Tugbyele 1953 (Box 8)
  - University of North Carolina Press 1955 (Box 8)
  - Vision 1955 (Box 8)
  - Vogue 1962 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence: "W" 1952-1965 (Box 8)
  - Rev. Wyatt Tee Walker, Gillfield Baptist Church, Petersburg, Virginia, and Virginia State Director, CORE 1958-1960 (Box 8)
  - Washington Post 1957-1963 (Box 8)
  - Mrs. J. Waties Waring 1950-1959 (Box 8)
  - The J. Waties Warings 1960-1965, n.d. (Box 8)
  - John W. Whetzel 1950-1952 (Box 8)
  - A. J. Whittenburg, President, Greenville, South Carolina Branch, NAACP 1958 (Box 8)
  - Roy Wilkins, Executive Secretary, NAACP 1959-1963 (Box 8)
  - Woman's Home Companion 1955-1956 (Box 8)
  - William Yardley, Rector, Chatham Hall 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - Unidentified correspondence 1951-1968, n.d. (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence 1949-1955, 5 folders (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence 1955-1958, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence 1959-1970, 6 folders (Box 11)
  - Correspondence between Sarah Patton Boyle and Her Supporters
    - Alexandria, Virginia 1963-1965 (Box 12)
    - Charlottesville, Virginia, articles re Civil Rights Movement in Virginia 1957-1958 (Box 12)
    - Charlottesville, Virginia 1962-1964 (Box 12)
    - Danville, Virginia 1962-1964 (Box 12)
    - Fredericksburg, Virginia 1958-1959 (Box 12)
    - Lynchburg, Virginia 1962-1965 (Box 12)
    - Norfolk, Virginia 1963-1964 (Box 12)
    - Norfolk, Virginia, papers re integration progress in Norfolk 1956 (Box 12)
    - Portsmouth, Virginia 1963-1964 (Box 12)
      Includes typed manuscript "A Parable of the Flowers: Suggested Prayer for use by 'Christian' Segregationists."
    - Richmond, Virginia 1962-1965 (Box 12)
    - Richmond, Virginia n.d. (Box 12)
      Contains preliminary data on canvassing effort of Richmond.
    - Roanoke, Virginia 1957-1958 (Box 12)
      Concerns Boyle's civil rights work in Roanoke.
    - Staunton, Virginia 1956-1957 (Box 12)
      These papers concern Boyle's integration efforts in Staunton.
    - Suffolk, Virginia 1956-1957 (Box 12)
      These papers concern Boyle's integration efforts in Suffolk.
    - California 1957 (Box 13)
    - Delaware 1963-1964 (Box 13)
    - Illinois 1963-1964 (Box 13)
    - Massachusetts 1961-1964 (Box 13)
    - New Jersey 1963-1964 (Box 13)
    - New York [Buffalo] 1963-1965 (Box 13)
    - New York [City] 1962-1965 (Box 13)
    - New York 1962-1965 (Box 14)
    - North Carolina 1963-1964 (Box 14)
    - Ohio 1963-1965 (Box 14)
    - Pennsylvania 1963-1964 (Box 14)
    - Tennessee 1957 (Box 14)
      Concerns Boyle's speech at Mt. Zion Baptist Church.
    - Virginia 1962-1964 (Box 14)
    - Washington, D. C. 1962-1964 (Box 14)
    - "Deep South" 1963-1965 (Box 15)
    - New England states [Maine, Vermont, Rhode Island] 1962-1964 (Box 15)
    - Western states 1963-1964 (Box 15)
    - Middle Western states 1963-1964 (Box 15)
    - Canada 1963-1964 (Box 15)
    - Foreign re Boyle's integration campaign 1963-1968 (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - Awards for Boyle, with newspaper and magazine articles 1956-1965, n.d. (Box 16)
    - Baptists 1952-1965 (Box 16)
    - Catholics 1952-1965, n.d. (Box 16)
    - Church of the Brethen 1968 (Box 16)
    - Congregational Church 1965-1966 (Box 16)
    - Episcopalians 1952-1963, n.d. (Box 16)
    - Lutheran Church 1952-1953 (Box 16)
    - Methodists 1952-1957 (Box 16)
    - Presbyterian Church 1951-1958 (Box 16)
    - Unitarian Church 1953 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous churchmen and church organizations 1952-1968, n.d. (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous papers and printed material re churches, including three copies of New South 1951-1968, n.d. (Box 16)
    - Invitations to speak 1954-1970, n.d., 5 folders (Box 17)
- Articles and Review by and About Sarah Patton Boyle
  - "And Yet They Will Win," Interracial Review 1958 Jul, 6 p. (Box 18)
  - "Are Rights Demonstrations Right," The Petal Paper, 3 p. and "'Rightness' of Demonstrations," Newsletter, 1 p. 1965 Apr (Box 18)
  - "Breaking an Illusion," Concern 1952 Mar 7, 3 p. (Box 18)
  - "Brotherhood," Community 1956 Feb, 1 p. (Box 18)
  - "Charlottesville Holds Danger--and Hope," The Southern Patriot 1958 Jun, 4 p., with TMs carbon (Box 18)
  - "Convention Guest Writes Impressions of Meeting," SCLC Newsletter 1963 Oct, 1 p. (Box 18)
  - "Dear Mr. Chamberlin:," Social Questions Bulletin 1957 Mar, 1 p. (Box 18)
  - "Dying Dream and Living Truth," Christian Century 1968 Oct 23, 9 p., TMs carbon (Box 18)
  - "The Evil Illusion," Episcopal Churchnews 1952 Mar 2 (Box 18)
    Includes attached article re James Dabb.
  - "Facts and Figures of Good Will, by A White Southern [S. P. B.]," n.d., 5 p.,TMs carbon (Box 18)
  - "Faith Can Move Mountains," n.d., 4 p.,TMs carbon (Box 18)
  - "Fear of Integration," Interraccial Review 1958 Feb, 3 p. (Box 18)
  - "A First-Hand Account of a Southern Sit-in," 1963 Jul, 3 p.,printed (Box 18)
  - "The Flight to Los Angeles," Parts I- III 1957 Nov, 9 p., with postcards (Box 18)
  - "From Behind the Segregation Curtain," re polling. n.d., 6 p.,TMs carbon (Box 18)
  - "Fulfillment of Three Dreams," SCLS Newsletter 1964 Jan, 1 p. (Box 18)
  - "God in the Spare Room," The Episcopalian 1964 Sep, 3 p. (Box 18)
  - "The Guilty Premise," n.d., 18 p. Speech,TMs (Box 18)
  - "How Long Halt Ye?," n.d., 4 p., TMs (Box 18)
  - "I Confront Tradition in the South," n.d., 9 p., TMs carbon (Box 18)
  - "I Defend Integration in the South," n.d., 15 p., TMs (Box 18)
  - "I Wonder if Preachers Know...," n.d., 4 p., TMs (Box 18)
  - "Inside a Segregationist," Ebony 1963 Jun, Includes TMs carbon and photographs. (Box 18)
  - "A Letter to be Remembered...," 1960 Apr 6, 1 p., printed (Box 18)
  - "Let's Order our Faith to March," 1951 May 13, TMs carbon and AMs with revisions. (Box 18)
    Includes attached polling slips.
  - "Mistaken Identity," 1964 Sep-Dec, 11 p., TMs (Box 18)
    Includes related correspondence between Boyle and Maxwell S. Stewart.
  - "My Own Conversion," The Interracial Review, 1957 Dec, 3 p. (Box 18)
  - "On Earth--A New Minority," SCLC Newsletter, 1963 Nov-Dec, 1 p. (Box 18)
  - "An Open Letter to Negroes of the South," n.d., 5 p., TMs carbon (Box 18)
  - "The Price of Brotherhood," Ebony, 1963 Apr 23, 7 p., with two TMs carbons (Box 18)
    One carbon has captions for pictures with mentioned picture of burning cross and Hallmark cards.
  - "The Racial Crisis: An Exchange of Letters," The Christian Century, 1968 May 22, 5 p., with TMs carbon, 17 p. (Box 18)
  - "Rocket to Freedom," 1958 Jan 15, 1 p., TMs memo (Box 18)
  - "The Root of the Race Problem." n.d., TMs and TMs carbon, with autograph revisions by Boyle (Box 18)
  - "Segregation is a Shell in the South" 1952, Two varied TMs: one with autograph revisions by Boyle, one TMs carbon (Box 18)
  - "The Song of a Jailbird," 1963-1969, ca. 30 items, AMs statements, TMs carbon (Box 18)
    Includes related correspondence, newspaper clippings, notes, and legal papers re Boyle's imprisonment in St. Augustine, Florida.
  - The Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC) Newsletter: articles by Boyle and related correspondence 1963-1964, 8 TMs carbons, printed articles, and newsletters (Box 18)
  - "Southern Racism is a Bogey Man," n.d., 16 p., TMs (Box 18)
  - "The Southern Tragedy of Errors," 1951 Dec, 12 p. (Box 18)
    Includes letter, Blake Clark to Boyle.
  - "A Southerner Looks at Integration," Religion and Labor, 1959 Feb, 3 p. (Box 18)
  - "Southerners Will Like Integration," Saturday Evening Post, 1955 Feb 19, Reprint and TMs carbon (Box 18)
    Includes royalty slips and notecards re public opinion, preview from Saturday Evening Post and broadside, with attached leaflet of opposition to the article.
  - "Spit in the Devil's Eye: A Southern Heretic Speaks...," The Nation, 1956 Oct 20, Reprint, TMs carbon, newspaper clipping. (Box 18)
    Includes reprint and TMs carbon with original name Segregation, Surprises and Theology," and November 17 issue of The Nation with article re Boyle, with attached newspaper clipping.
  - "The Story of an Article...," The Nation 1957 Apr 17, Includes TMs carbon (Box 18)
  - "We Say to Our Brothers, 'Thou Fool'!" 1952, 6 p., TMs carbon (Box 18)
  - "A Voice from the South," Christian Century, 1952 Dec 17, 6 p. (Box 18)
  - "What Does Brotherhood Mean?" Telefact, with related letter, Dorothy C. Guinn, National Council of Negro Women, Inc. to Boyle, with enclosure 1957 Feb (Box 18)
  - "What Southern Negroes Offer," n.d., 3 p., TMs (Box 18)
  - "Where Are the Decent Southerners?" n.d., 23 p., TMs carbon (Box 18)
  - "Why I Believe in Integration," The Virginia Spectator, 1957 May, 2 p., with two TMs carbons with revisions, 10 p. (Box 18)
  - "The Witness of a Lone Layman," n.d., 6 p., Tms carbon (Box 18)
  - "1. The Years of Destruction" and "3. Afterword," both from The Back Together Heart, n.d., TMs portions: 1: four copies, two rough drafts with autograph revisions by Boyle and three carbons. 3: three copies, one with autograph revisions by Boyle and two carbons. ca. 40 p. (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified writings of Boyle 1951-1960, n.d., TMs carbons and AMs papers (Box 18)
  - Reviews of The Desegregated Heart--correspondence and TMs review 1962 (Box 19)
  - Reviews of The Desegregated Heart 1962 (Box 19)
  - Review (newspaper) of The Desegregated Heart 1962 (Box 19)
  - "Moderate Southerners" supporter mail re The Desegregated Heart, including two letters from Andrew Lytle 1962-1965 (Box 19)
  - Notes for articles and letters re book prospect 1955 (Box 19)
  - "Notes for a Book" dated "Late 1950's" 1950s (Box 19)
  - Pre-Publication reactions to The Desegregated Heart. 1962 (Box 19)
    Blurbs by Bishop Pike, Martin Luther King, Kenneth B. Clark, and Harry Golden.
  - Publication of The Desegregated Heart 1962 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence from black readers of The Desegregated Heart 1962-1963 (Box 19)
  - Mailing lists and miscellaneous papers re The Desegregated Heart n.d. (Box 19)
  - Orders for Boyle's books 1962-1969 (Box 20)
  - "For Human Beings Only," n.d., 110 p., TMs carbon (Box 20)
  - Mailing lists and miscellaneous papers re "For Human Beings Only" n.d. (Box 20)
  - Reviews of "For Human Beings Only" 1964-1965 (Box 20)
  - Readers opinions and reviews of "For Human Beings Only" 1963-1965 (Box 20)
  - Speeches and drafts 1954, 9 TMs carbons (Box 21)
  - Transcription of interview held with Boyle by the Institute for Religious and Social Studies--"How to Effect Change? How Should Change Come?" 1966 Oct 18 (Box 21)
  - Broadcasts of "Defenders of State Sovereignty and Individual Liberties" 1957 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence preparatory to and in response to Boyle's radio interviews and television appearances 1955-1968 (Box 21)
  - Notes for speeches and plans 1947-1952 (Box 21)
  - Speeches and drafts 1952 (Box 21)
  - Drafts of speeches written by Boyle for a course in Speech Writing taken at the University of Virginia 1952-1954 (Box 21)
  - Speeches and drafts 1953 (Box 21)
  - Speeches and drafts 1955 (Box 21)
  - Newspaper clippings re Boyle's speeches of 1955 1955 Feb-Dec (Box 21)
  - Speeches and drafts, including two letters re speeches 1956 (Box 21)
  - Speeches and drafts 1957 (Box 21)
  - Speeches and drafts, including related correspondence 1958 (Box 22)
  - Speeches and drafts 1959 (Box 22)
  - Speeches and drafts 1960 (Box 22)
  - Speeches delivered to young people [1962] (Box 22)
  - Speeches and drafts 1963 (Box 22)
  - Speeches and drafts 1965-1966 (Box 22)
  - Newspaper clippings and bulletins re Boyle's speeches 1968 (Box 22)
  - Speeches and drafts by Boyle on integration [1964] (Box 22)
  - Speeches and drafts n.d. (Box 22)
  - Newspaper editorial re integration 1947 Aug 14 (Box 23)
  - Newspaper clippings, Boyle's first "Letter to the Editor" 1950 (Box 23)
  - Drafts of letters to the editor of various Virginia newspapers 1950-1954 (Box 23)
    Includes correspondence re editorials in black notebook.
  - Manuscript material preparatory to "Letters to the Editor" 1951 (Box 23)
  - "Letters to the Editor" re desegregation 1951-1952 (Box 23)
  - Articles written and ghostwritten by Boyle on integration and equality 1951 (Box 23)
  - "Letters to the Editor" with related material 1951-1953 (Box 23)
  - "Letters to the Editor" by Boyle and others, with related correspondence 1951-1960 (Box 23)
  - "Letters to the Editor" 1952 (Box 24)
  - Articles written by Boyle for the Roanoke Tribune 1952-1963 (Box 24)
  - "Letters to the Editor" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Articles written on the evils of segregation 1953 (Box 24)
  - "Letters to the Editor" by and about Boyle 1954-1955 (Box 24)
  - Editorials on integration 1955 (Box 24)
  - "Letters to the Editor" 1956 (Box 24)
  - "Letters to the Editor," 1957 (Box 24)
    Includes one quote from Jess Ogden.
  - "Letters to the Editor" and editorials on segregation 1958 (Box 24)
  - "Letters to the Editor" re segregation 1959 (Box 24)
  - "Letters to the Editor" 1960 (Box 24)
  - "Letters to the Editor" and related correspondence 1961-1964 (Box 24)
  - "Letters to the Editor" 1965 (Box 24)
  - Letters to "Dear White-So" n.d. (Box 24)
  - Book review drafts and clippings; Correspondence re: Boyle's tenure as reviewer for racially oriented books for the Richmond Times-Dispatch 1951-1955, In blue notebook. (Box 25)
  - Editorials written to the Charlottesville Tribune, The Journal and Guide, and other Negro publications. 1951-1953, Includes carbon typescripts of "From Behind the Curtain" series and "Facts and Figures of Good Will" series, in blue notebook. (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, manuscripts, and newspaper clippings re reviews by Boyle 1963 (Box 25)
  - Pamphlets re the NAACP 1914-1915, 1951-1960 (Box 26)
  - Newspaper clippings re the NAACP 1951-1960 (Box 26)
    Includes a copy of Afro magazine section.
  - Miscellaneous papers re the NAACP 1951-1964 (Box 26)
    Includes 1954 membership card of Boyle; and letter from Boyle to "Charlottesville Branch of the NAACP."
  - Newspaper clippings re integration success 1953 (Box 26)
  - Advertisement carbons with attached newspaper clippings, paid by the Charlottesville branch of the NAACP, including planning sheet, and correspondence; letter, April 1, 1960, from J. Edgar Hoover to Boyle; letter, April 14, 1947, from Hoover to Walter White, Secretary, NAACP. 1947, 1960-1961 (Box 26)
  - Miscellaneous material re local desegregation campaign 1951-1960 (Box 26)